Okay, now we begin. Turn off your
phone. Please don't go outside or
walk around
except in an emergency, except for a baby emergency.
Nico, let's go. Okay,
what happened? He had something
stuck in his throat.
You taught the lion's dance, and
thank you to everyone.
We have a pediatrician here.
Thank you for being here. It's really
a good feeling for parents to have a
pediatrician.
One more minute
since it's time.
Now we begin. A
Mona Lisa smile, a small
smile, and try to maintain it throughout the
entire meditation. Your
eyelids are relaxed.
Try to be relaxed. Don't take
your yoga too seriously, and don't take meditation too seriously. Don't tense up. Don't try too hard.
It's a beautiful day.
We have a beautiful Lake Alaba right outside.
We're sitting with wonderful friends.
We have a good yoga class, and I
have great cappuccino. Everything is relaxed. Relax your
fingers. Gently tense your stomach; this
will straighten your spine.
Relax your forehead, as
smooth as a baby's, and then
slowly come to your breath, and then
begin...  Follow your breath
very gently and with joy. Follow
your breath. Try not to think about so many
other things.
Long exhale,
and then we put ourselves in the state of mind of desire.
You can concentrate on a
sound in the room.
Here in this room, today we have a
loud air conditioner, for example. We have birds
chirping outside, and outside there are
hotel staff making noises,
or someone here in the room coughs or
makes other noises. Pick one of these.
For me, it's the air conditioner.
Choose one and concentrate
on the state of mind in the realm of desire.
Each stage, even in the guardian formless realm,
is an exercise in comparison.
We compare the stage we are at,
for example, the air conditioner in the realm
of desire, and then we compare
it with the stage that delves further into
the object. And the next object
we choose is the first stage of the farm
realm.
It's the stage where, if you meditate a lot there
or die in this state of mind, it brings about
a rebirth in the antechamber,
and we  Now, let's make the comparison with
our heartbeat. Now, shift your
attention from the air conditioner to
your heartbeat in your chest,
and you will naturally feel
that it is much quieter and calmer
to follow the heartbeat instead of the
air conditioner. The rough attention of
your mind notices things (in
Sanskrit, vitara), which is now focused on the
air conditioner, and the other
part of the mind that wants to delve deeper (
ara) goes to the heartbeat.
This is similar to when you hear a song playing
from a loudspeaker in a supermarket.
This is stronger,
and then it's similar to when you
stand in the supermarket and
try to hear a detail of the
song. This is like zara, that it then
delves deeper into the object,
examines the object. So, classically,
when you go from the realm of desire, the
realm of the forum, then there is a rough
attention on the air conditioner, and
your examination, the deeper delving,
that is,
looking into the realm of the forums and hearing the quiet beating of your heart there,
very slowly,
focusing on the  air conditioning
and then looks out into the realm of form, into
the still beating of your
heart, and goes there.
You are outside the heart. You
observe the heart. The
transition will take a few minutes.
Each stage we progress through in this meditation
requires a juggler of
meditation.
You will leave something behind because it
is not as still as the place you
want to go to,
and the process of leaving something behind
that is not as quiet as the place
you want to go to takes a few
minutes.
Now we take a few minutes
for the transition to the heartbeat.
Then you become aware that
concentrating on the heartbeat
allows the planner to flow calmly on the one hand,
and aligns your body on the other.
It is a pleasant relaxation because
it is so calm in the heartbeat.
Now we go from the first stage of the realm of
form to the second.
Now the two mental functions
of perceiving the heartbeat
and investigating the heartbeat
become Sharia. Now, when we enter the second
stage,
we completely leave these two qualities of mind behind.
We will no longer observe the heartbeat,
but we are the
heartbeat.
Trying to make this second transition,
let these pits of mental states
check, perceive, notice behind
you,
and then dive deep into the object, become the
heartbeat.
You are still aware of the comfortable
posture and alignment of your body,
especially if you do yoga every day,
and then you still have this pleasant
feeling because it is much nicer to be the
heartbeat instead of
observing it.
Now we move on to the third stage of
the Form Realm. The big difference
here is
that the pleasant feeling of the still
mind now becomes an obstacle,
and you dive even deeper into the object.
Now you no longer think, "Everything is so
beautiful, it is so still."
You are simply still without thinking
how beautiful it is. An even deeper level of
stillness.
At this stage, the two
tools of meditation are very strongly
developed. Shooting a smoke detector is
very sensitive when the mind tries
to wander back to the air conditioner, or
when it tries to watch the heartbeat
instead of being the heartbeat,
or even when you  You
say to yourself, "This place is so beautiful, so quiet,"
then the smoke detector will make a very
quiet baby beep beep in your mind.
The mind is back at the air conditioner,
and then there's another
meditation tool in your mind.
It's like a rope with a loop,
and it catches the mind that's
focused on the air conditioner
and then pulls it back into this
heartbeat. The heartbeat—
now we are the heartbeat and know we're
deeply immersed on the third level
of this realm, even deeper than you can
think. It's so beautiful and still here.
We've gone to an even faster place.
We're moving on to the fourth level
of this realm.
The pleasant alignment of the
body, especially if you
practice yoga regularly,
we're now leaving behind.
It's a distraction on the fourth
level
that you're aware of and how pleasant it
feels when you have such good
posture.
This feeling—every time we
go to the next level, we eliminate
something. On the fourth level, focus
on the deep stillness.
Beyond a pleasant mental
and physical posture and feeling,
I am making a
special effort to concentrate you on one point.
Create the feeling of concentration on
one point
beyond physical and emotional
sensations.
We will stay here for a few minutes, still
within the heartbeat.
Now we move on to the first stage
of the harmless realm, called taking part—
or endless space. Take this one
point, stay on this one point,
leave the beating heart behind you,
just this one point, far away
from noticing and
checking,
beyond the pleasant feeling of
posture and the pleasant feeling of
stillness. The
body feels as if it is
anesthetized.
We are in a single point, and
we will take this to the next stage.
Now think about the space in which
our earth, the planets, the stars are
located, and from this one point, they expand.
Expand this point of
concentration,
the world for me. It is easier for me if
I move on the horizontal plane.
It is easier for me if
I only imagine moving to the
right and left.  Expanding as you
become more experienced in meditation,
you can then also include front and back,
and above and below.
Imagine your mind spreading out in all
directions from this one point,
and as the next few minutes go on,
your mind simply expands further and further in
all directions. No sensation
of body or mind.
Now we go into the second stage of the
formless realm. We always leave something
behind us to dive deeper, to
dive even deeper.
In the first stage of the formless realm, we
imagined how the one point of
mind spread out in space like a boat
on the sea. We
used space to be aware of our position,
but even that distracts us. Now, in
the second stage of the formless
realm, we let go of the idea of
infinite space.
We leave behind the idea of ​​a space
that shows us where we are,
and we dive into
pure consciousness. No more reference points.
We meditate within infinite
consciousness.
Even the idea of ​​infinite
Consciousness requires new effort;
it diminishes our concentration. We
move on to the third stage of the
formless realm. What do we leave behind?
That the idea of
infinite consciousness is behind you. It gives it away, and we move on, holding onto
nothing anymore. It is
simply nothing, no holder, no holding on,
and nothing to cling to.
That infinite
consciousness is gone.
Now we move on to the fourth stage of the spaceless realm.
It takes some effort to think
there is nothing. I am holding onto nothing.
Let us go to the deepest point. The
effort of holding onto nothing feels
like darkness,
and all the stages before felt like
distractions. The effort
that distracts us.
In the fourth stage of the formless
realm, I choose not to choose.
I will not
focus on any particular object, like
infinite consciousness, and I
also choose not to concentrate on it and to hold onto
nothing.
Beyond any choice, I
choose an even deeper journey into
nothingness.
Now that my mind is in a
beautiful place...  Once I find myself in this state, I will
begin literal meditation. I
will visualize a sacred object before my mind,
a
teacher, and the teaching time of this teacher.
The new states of mind so far,
starting with the air conditioning, through the
four stages of the discipline, through the
four stages of the formless realm—these
are exercises to train my ability to
meditate.
They feel good,
feel like real meditation.
I have found places in meditation
that I have never reached before,
but I understand that they are only tools;
they are not the goal itself. You
can compare it to building a
good microscope. The point is not
the microscope, the point. What would I be
under the microscope after I
built it? I have understood that
these eight stages are very attractive;
they are addictive, almost like a
knock.
But I know that in order to help myself and others,
I must tune this
microscope to something sacred.
I have chosen my heart's teacher,
any teacher from your life who has
really helped you a lot. Your
parents are very powerful objects for
everyone.  A teacher at school, a
teacher in vocational training, and your
spiritual teachers or priests—choose
one
and bring it before your mind so that he
meditates with you. Imagine
you're not focusing on a picture
or a statue;
we're focusing on
a real person. The
body moves with the breath, the
eyes blink, a smile on the
face,
and they exude the scent of a good
person.
Even this teacher has teachings.
What is the teaching time of this teacher?
There is no teacher in my life
who came into my life without a strange
seed. Now, the teacher
sitting across from me now comes from
a strange seed in my mind.
Beautiful silver seeds in my
mind;
they open, and little pictures of
the lama come out,
one after the other, and they reveal
themselves to my mind. And that's it. When
I meditate on my lama for a
minute, I tried to imagine this
silver seed in your mind. Imagine
how the seed opens,
tried to imagine the lama emerging from
the  A seed arises,
it's an image, but a perfect image.
It's a real lama,
and he can teach more about becoming a mother.
Try to imagine the silver frames to her,
and try to
imagine how the lama comes from the seed.
As long as I have these seeds,
I will have a lama. As long as
I have these seeds, I will have
a lama.
Who planted the seeds in my mind?
I did. When, mainly
in my past
lives, can you remember how you
planted a seed? Probably
not. The memory is somewhere in
your mind.
So let's pretend that we
remember.
Think of your lama. I'm making you
aware of the karmic laws. A law
number one came to mind:
all the forces that created this type of
lama for me. The seeds must be
similar. Second karmic law: I've
known my lama for 45, 10 years now,
but the ceramic cause was
perhaps only a few days.
Perhaps it was a very special
hour that I
spent with him in one of my
past lives.
It may be that they  They were a completely different
person if I now
have a male lama; perhaps it was
a woman if he is now American;
perhaps it was Saudi Arabia;
perhaps I myself was a
completely different person, equally rich,
female; perhaps I was male;
perhaps I lived in a different
country;
perhaps the seed was
planted thousands of years ago. If we cannot now
remember how we
planted these numbers for the lama,
what we pretend to
remember—
let your imagination be completely free
and open; make a film—
adventure, novel, romance, beautiful, a
wonderful story of his
past lives. Everything that is a field
because everything that is a field at the moment
comes from the same seed that also
creates your lama. And if you
do this meditation regularly,
you will be able to
look backward in the Council of Life,
to see into the past, and you will
see the real events that cause a present
life. Five minutes about
your very own film every day
for the next 30 days. For the
challenges, every day you can
make it bigger, you can add more details.
Five minutes about
meeting  To you and your life in
past lives,
the event that planted this silver seed
in a mind,
and then return to the present in
a meditation.
If my lover arises from this seed,
then my lover suffers because
he means hai. There is no lama in
my life that I have not created.
Now return to the breath,
three long exhalations. With each exhalation,
golden light flows from you, and that
reaches all people in this world. You
share with them the good agrar, the good
karama of this meditation with every
living being.
Then you can slowly
open your eyes, stretch. This is called the Dance of the
Lion.
It was taught by the future Bodamer,
Basanga, 1700 years ago, and
booties use it after they
have directly experienced the teaching time in the
following minutes to
better understand the teaching time
and the Wheel of Life.